{
  "reference_number": "9575",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": "Climate fear is being used to take away human freedom and empower governments. \"We are not going to change the world by\n\n tinkering around with nonsense.\" (Piers Corbyn)"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Carbon Dioxide - Reducing net carbon dioxide emissions to zero by 2050",
      "answer_index": 13,
      "notes": "There is no observation that shows CO2 warming this planet's atmosphere. No evidence that an increase of CO2 by 0.01% in the\n atmosphere alters the climate significantly. Methane is broken up very quickly in the atmosphere by sunlight and chemical reactions.\n\n It is a trace gas, essential to life. The idea that it is a more powerful greenhouse gas than CO2 is an ignorant lie, which is repeated by\n propaganda over and over again. \"Of course you can't kill all of the methane bacteria, or the cow would die\" (Dr Kai Grevsen)"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions (including from new forest planting) and using some emissions reductions from overseas (international carbon units) that have strong environmental safeguards",
      "answer_index": 2,
      "notes": "Forests ruin productive land which can be used for food crops. There is environmental damage when they are harvested. There\n\n needs to be different varieties of trees to suit the locations chosen."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "We are always told that the revenue from emissions trading, or carbon taxes, will be used for energy and climate change adaptation\n purposes. THAT IS AN OBVIOUS LIE ! Politicians regard it as a new revenue source. No one should fall for the carbon tax trap."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "It is planned to make the climate crises industry so enormous that no one will be able to dismantle it, even as computer models and\n disaster claims totally lose credibility."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": "All acts in NZ can currently be changed through due process under exceptional circumstances."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Emission budgets cannot be increased, unless the government changes the act through the usual parliamentary process. If there\nare exceptional circumstances the government can change the zero carbon act."
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Regulators, researchers, universities, businesses, manufacturers, pressure groups, journalists, and politicians now have such strong\nmonetary, reputational and authority interests in climate alarmism that they will defend its tenets and largesse tooth and nail. They\n\nshould consider the scientific knowledge about climate change, the technology relevant to their plans, the economic circumstances\nand competiveness of particular sectors. The fiscal circumstances apparent at the time, with regards to taxation, public spending and\n\nborrowing."
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The Government needs to keep reality in mind. By raising costs throughout the country, attacking the agricultural sector and the\ntransport sector, productivity will collapse, our economy will be damaged, our money will be squandered."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "The commission can also advise how NZ stays within these these budgets, how NZ can best adapt to climate change, and monitor\n\nprogress on NZ's emission reductions. The Climate Change Commission will be a vast money wasting bureaucracy. People will be\nrequired to waste precious time on emission budgets, adaptation plans and emission targets. They will be monitored and\n\ninvestigated. Lose their livelyhood and privacy. All for a devious and fraudulent hoax."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Advising the Government on policy settings in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 6,
      "notes": "The commission must also identify the extent of regressive impacts from proposed ETS settings, and propose effective\ncomplementary policies which fairly compensate vulnerable households. The Climate Change Commission is not capable of making\ndecisions itself, in respect of the number of available units in the ETS. The IPCC has not provided convincing evidence, based on\n\nobservations of the real world, that man-made greenhouse gases cause dangerous global warming. So the Climate Change\nCommission is ignorant of the facts required to make a judgement according to the ETS."
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "It is important that scientific knowledge and practical experience be a major expertise. Mechanical and engineering skills are also\nimportant, as well as experience in the health/hospital sector. The Commissioners should all be trustworthy, hardworking and reliable\n\nmembers of society. ."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "This is an important area. Even though the science of climate change and its causes is devious and corrupt. Climate change will\n\nhappen anyway, and adapting to climate change and adverse effects related to it has to be planned for. It is always prudent to be\nprepared and historically, actions to avoid and lessen disaster have already been discovered. Such important activities as drainage\n\nand regular maintenance of waterways, by dredging and deepening channels, have been allowed to lapse. Houses have also been\nbuilt on what had been flood plains in the past."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Care must be taken with adaptation policies to ensure that climate damaging emissions are not increased"
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "This will end up with public money being spent to entrench the lie. Not-for-profit organisations will be chosen to \"empower local\nleaders with skills and tools to build more climate resilient communities\".\" To develop vulnerability assessments, response plans, as\n\nwell as tools and case studies for future sharing\"."
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "These 8 words are the death of climate change - \"It violates the Equivalence Principle, therefore it's wrong.\" The Equivalence Principle\n\nsays - If data cannot distinguish between two things, then the two things are identical. The IPCC claims human emissions will linger in\nthe atmosphere for hundreds of years, and 15% will remain forever. That claim violates the Equivalence Principle. Nature's CO2 has a\n\nhalf life in the atmosphere of only 2.8 years. Therefore human CO2 also has a half life of 2.8 years. Nature cannot distinguish between\nthe two sources."
    }
  ]
}
